JORDAN S. BENJAMIN

PURSUING A CAREER IN SOFTWARE & WEB DEVELOPMENT

CONTACT

0431916656

jordansbenjamin@gmail.com

</> jordansbenjamin.vercel.app

in linkedln.com/in/jordansb

github.com/jordansbenjamin



Sydney, Australia

EDUCATION

HIGHER EDUCATION DIPLOMA,

Information Technology Academy of Interactive Technology (Coder Academy) 2023

BACHELOR'S DEGREE,

Film & TV Australian Film, Television & Radio school 2017 - 2020

SHORT COURSE,

Foundations in Film & TV Victorian College of the Arts 2016

SKILLS

| Web Development

HTMI

CSS / SCSS

Bootstrap / Tailwind

Python

Flask

JavaScript / TypeScript

React / Next.js

Express / Node

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

SUMMARY

Recently venturing into the world of software and web development, I am currently pursuing a diploma in IT and have achieved a high distinction and seeking a junior developer role for 2024. I bring with me over 5 years of experience from the Australian film, TV, and photography industry, where I established myself as a skilled camera and lighting technician. My background has equipped me with skills in collaboration, problem-solving, and both creative and technical expertise across diverse projects. I am enthusiastic about merging my creative industry experience with software programming skills to offer a unique contribution to the tech industry.

PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

PHOTOGRAPHERS ASSISTANT

Freelance | 2021 — 2023

Mainly worked in the Australian Fashion photography industry with some experience in advertising photography, worked with some of premier fashion brands and renowned photographers in Australia. The dynamic nature of fashion photography demanded rapid adaptability and quick decision-making.

- Proficient in diverse photography camera systems, understanding the nuances of lighting technically and creatively..
- Excelled in high-pressure environments, ensuring swift turnarounds and seamless adaptability to ever-changing set requirements.
- Coordinated and communicated effectively with various departments, ensuring a cohesive workflow in photography sets.

CAMERA & LIGHTING TECHNICIAN

Freelance | 2017 — 2023

Engaged in diverse film projects, from TV shows for platforms like Netflix and Stan to TVC's for clients such as Virgin Airlines, Adobe, and Tourism Australia. Being apart of the camera and lighting department requires proactive problem-solving.

- Demonstrated proficiency across Camera and Lighting departments, while also gaining insights and understanding of other departments in a film set.
- Recognised for the ability to swiftly diagnose issues and implement solutions, ensuring minimal disruptions during shoots.
- · Fostered strong relationships with various film set departments, ensuring smooth operations and clear correspondence.

JORDAN S. BENJAMIN

PURSUING A CAREER IN SOFTWARE & WEB DEVELOPMENT

SKILLS

| Software

Data structures and algorithms

Discrete Mathematics

OOP / Functional Programming

Agile Methodology

Software testing (TDD / Pytest / Jest)

Git / GitHub (Source control)

RESTful API's

Bash Scripting

Postman / Insomnia (API testing)

Vercel

Netlify

Heroku

Figma (Wireframing / mockups)

Relational Database Schema Design

| Media

Adobe Premiere Pro

Adobe Lightroom

Adobe Photoshop

DaVinci Resolve

Canva (Presentations)

SELECTED SOFTWARE & WEB PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO V2

jordansbenjamin.vercel.app

https://github.com/jordansbenjamin/portfolio_v2

Second iteration of my portfolio website, it is built with the latest technologies.

- Developed entirely with React (Next.js 14) and TypeScript.
- Utilised React Email and Resend.
- Styled with Tailwind and Framer Motion.

CINEMATICA RESTful API

https://github.com/jordansbenjamin/Cinematica_API

Cinematica is a RESTful API developed as my third major project for the Diploma of IT course I'm undertaking. Cinematica is an API that allows users to review, rate and catalog movies. Inspired by Letterboxd.

- The project was planned, tracked and managed by Trello as a project management tool.
- Developed with Python and Flask with MVC architecture.
- PostgreSQL is used as the relational database management system.
- Flask SQLAlchemy is used as the ORM.
- The API itself has full CRUD functionality with authentication and authorization.
- Full documentation of each endpoint of the API.

KAZOOT PYTHON GUI APP

https://github.com/jordansbenjamin/Kazoot_PyProject

Kazoot is a quiz based application inspired by Kahoot! It was developed as a study aid, it provided with a valuable learning experience to solve a problem I had and helped me achieve 95% on my Discrete Mathematics exam.

- Developed entirely with Python and the Tkinter module.
- The application was built using Object Oriented Programming principles in Python.

SOFTWARE RELATED CERTIFICATIONS

GOOGLE UX DESIGN CERTIFICATE

Coursera / Google / 2023

META FRONT-END DEVELOPER PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Coursera / Meta / 2023

GOOGLE IT SUPPORT CERTIFICATE

Coursera / Google / 2023